welcome Nadav to our project raising
we're gonna be raising his project
digital native academic it stands for
DNA hey education honest a reform but I
feel like there's a much better word
than that cryptocurrency all all in
London so if you wonder community good
of what that is and then what you want
out of this hour what you want us to
concentrate on to raise for your project
then we can do that okay thank you so I
am I have a timer here so I will manage
time so you don't have to look at the
clock to worry about it you can be with
me I've only got five minutes to start
all right I'll try to take less than
that I'll just talk about me for a
second a little bit about the past
president future just in you know one
minute II and then I can talk about the
ask for today what I would love to get
from this and I hope we can get into
more detail with the event cycles we
have them coming up at that'll be after
2 I don't know if people are Bitcoin
people but it's kind of like I feel like
we're a 2008 of Bitcoin you know like
the device exists we I'm seeing this
momentum and interest that I've been
working on this for 20 years you know
and suddenly people are ready for this
such exciting I have in the last 18
years in the part of education here in
New York City working in Central Harlem
I was a physics teacher I ran a robotics
program the first all minority program
to be reg nationally so we beat all the
New York City private schools and public
schools and then went on to beat many
more year after year and then turned it
on a failing high school for at-risk
kids so a kid a place where the kids
that have dropped out of school we
picked them up and bring them back in
and it was a listed to be shut down in
newspapers four months after I took over
and then less than two years later we
were at a school well developed
maintained our you know rate so they
couldn't shut us down we dodged that
which was rare and it's a testament to
my staff and my students not to me I am
leadership support to them and so all
the work that I'm presenting here is I
gave it up stolen from my staff who are
the experts the the
engineer before that Digital Equipment
Corporation before this and so I'm not
going to get any more about me the
future let's start there and go the
other way so DNA credits digital native
oh no we lost our girl out just at the
time yes we'll give them a minute yes
the pot back in really the only person
that we need to stay through the whole
let's not education and currency that we
don't quite understand as anyone
everyone read the lower document my
apologies to Eric who got it like an
hour ago
yeah I skimmed it I skimmed it I got
some I've got some sense of it I didn't
read it properly properly but I do that
some sense but yeah I mean to be honest
he absolutely preaching to the choir he
didn't need to convert me I mean there's
only the last couple of pages which is
actually the thing itself the rest of it
is a lead-up cert and why it's important
and you know all the ways in which the
current modality fucks everything up and
so which I'm absolutely completely on
board with so yeah I did not see the
word doc how was that shared I believe I
shared it in the f o WF previously yeah
the Google Doc that's above oh there we
go I see it click on that to make sure
no that's projects that's our I've gotta
open in another tab I can paste it in
that's it all right yeah I just missed
it
well I could definitely do with him
explaining the system itself because I
don't really understand it I mean I
absolutely understand the philosophy
behind it but the mechanics I don't
really understand so much the same I
love the idea of improving education
very interested to here's approach hmm
no I was I have all the questions about
the cryptocurrency like wait how do you
I just had generate in and how is it
allocated I miss the part of or even
those things that have to do with
education I mean I haven't read yeah
I've read the word narcho I mean the
document at all but does it just my
understanding before he gets here other
than other than you know sitting exams
and and and so you know going jumping
through the traditional groups it's
another way of generating credit
you know a credit of attainment for the
student and for the and for and for
teachers as well it can go both ways as
I said I don't fully understand it but
that's that's the notion behind it I
mean it seems to me a necessary first
step not wanting to use this as a forum
for my own for my own projects or
anything but I mean it sounds like a
really great first step would be to get
rid of standardized testing I've been
just get rid of it first of all you know
what I mean and prepare the ground for a
brand new structure yeah maybe we can
kind of just discuss things in the same
area until he comes back
I don't know Jubilee are you able to
chat with him somewhere else oh yeah I
just send him a message ask if he's
coming back but it's not green you don't
even there's a choice online he may have
lost his internet connection
yeah but Erica that would be an
interesting discussion I agree that
standardized testing has its challenges
and it seems to have had a negative
effect over the last decade since we
implemented it in the States very
strongly but I am not aware of any
alternatives that also have the that
solved the problems that it did to some
extent solve what was that be an
interesting conversation so so so one of
the problems was an inconsistency in
education so that level caught a lot of
people were being not educated so we
still have that problem they did it
because some people are just passing
kids on the tests and cheating and stuff
but there was a big problem where easier
and they changed the great boundaries
different states to accommodate the
actual scores of the kids and all of
this kind of thing I mean it's a
nonsense well yes but that's all
implementation that doesn't say that
standardized testing is bad that says
that proves the implementation is bad so
it still might
it's there still might be a better
solution but I don't I don't think just
taking it away is that may be better
than where we're at as the
implementation was so bad but rather
than doing a fairly decent
implementation of it would still might
be better than the status quo before we
started doing it and what what about the
problems that it creates that I outlined
do you see those as being either saved
in the frame or not in particular
problems I didn't dig into your post I
wanted to we didn't find the priority so
if you want to state those we can keep
discussing another topic I'll do my best
talking about the future yeah and then
and then you disappeared yeah and you
can still see me now yes what the hell
happened oh my god I'm so embarrassed
okay well there we go so should I just
jump back in I don't know I'll set it
for two minutes we're not very direct
all the timing so okay oh you're not
okay okay good so I'll just let's sorry
everybody
okay I'm back so a true digital native
my set is a return to humanity right we
were robotic and industrial age in the
digital age we have robots to do the
robotic paper-pushing number-crunching
stuff so there's a return to our
humanity digital aid it wouldn't be
somebody that's captured by digital
devices giving their attention to
somebody else the benefit it's somebody
that knows how to manage their attention
so we're mindfulness or work ethic using
your attention to produce work so the
whole basis of this system is quality
student work work that is the digital
that's how we build academic capital and
this whole the the event cycles that
I'll talk about if we go into a little
more detail about how it works are based
out of a community coming together like
we're going to do here in Harlem or we
have been doing and got interrupted but
we're going to restart
and you produce high-quality academic
content with that's for you know the
kids produce it and you guide them I
could talk about let me just skip right
hold on I think you guys get most of the
context of that kind of that coercive
top-down educational model was good for
industrial education it just doesn't
work anymore for us in a digital age and
so where we are now in life is unit uh
but and and just all if you wouldn't
mind at least initially focusing on the
mechanics of the system itself how that
functions yeah that would that would be
I think really that's all of us yeah
yeah okay okay so beautiful that's what
I figured
um I already I'm in a weird twilight
zone sir and he said all this stuff two
seconds ago and as to remember that you
guys been hearing it the ask should I
talk about that because you're talking
about getting into detail I think it
helps us to if we know that ask as you
go right through the detail that helps
us put it in context exactly let me just
say the ask and then I'll jump into
detail about how it's built beautiful
thank you so we have a non-profit that's
got like 30 grand that needs to be
revived so you know I could probably go
three board members but if people are
interested
my alarm sorry that's one piece is
reviving that nonprofit and then host
starting these cycles of events that
I'll talk about I have a book coming out
I mean I'm Stage four of having a book
kind of I have a final manuscript it's
been edited by a great editor the cover
design is almost done and it's just that
last step to publish I just decided to
not use the publisher that was you know
I'm gonna just do it myself
baby knows about that I've must feedback
on that that's number two and then the I
think the most important I should have
put it first is this site for that
nonprofit I wanted to be a funnel using
the book to funnel people into our
distribution list of updates to then
have them show up at events here in
Harlem first and then maybe other places
so that's really where the core core of
my work is people somebody knows how to
build those funnels to get from interest
in podcast so I go speak on podcasts to
get interest to a site but then I
collect email addresses and then I
didn't get people at events
um okay so how it works any questions
before I say anything else about the ask
great no yeah yay so we're gonna launch
I'm not principal of high school right
now so we're just going to recreate what
we had running there for ten to seven
years I was there we had a $500,000
recording studio and something that we
don't have acts but I think it's better
to do it in this more distributed way
actually you know when a distributed
entity gets a decentralized and you gets
attacked it just becomes more
decentralized so I think that the
attacks that I've dealt with are
actually just made this movement
stronger um so the first event we're
gonna 30k with whatever left after board
insurance we're going to bring back all
the kids that I've worked with that I've
made these pieces with in the past who
who inspired me to do this we're gonna
have an event for them only a private
event for them introduce this concept to
them and have some my staff that will be
that they're already part of this to
think about some early pieces that they
could do and see who's available and
who's interested and start developing
educational capital there now the system
I have it worked out from kind of
playing with things for so long but I
think the way to design it wouldn't
would be to build demand for technology
instead of building technology to create
imagine a demand so I just want to have
these invention if we could have some
engineers present listening they could
pricy tools that would serve us to then
be able to you know my wife sister is
building the same thing in Japan and
she's dying to have some shared
resources there and there's a whole
movement in Japan to opt out of high
school completely and so there are three
so I'm just gonna talk about kind of how
it's built socially in these events and
I can get down I'm a software engineer
that's where I started my career now
that's where my heart is so I can get
more and more into detail as you guys
ask but I really think the important
thing now isn't to worry about detail
let it arise naturally from our
interactions doing these things if we
have the right people in the room so the
events there are three levels that
remodel we're using and I should give
credit to the guy the credits I don't
know his name off top my head but a lab
it
is where we imagine projects for
students in terms of how to guide them
through so they can have be successful
in producing high quality content not
fail at that the studio where we work
with students it's what we call Super
Saturday in my school we all come
together on a Saturday a few Saturdays
in a row and work with the kids and see
what work they've done and get feedback
right that's the studio and then the
salon where we share the kids work at
the end and show the ones that earn the
credit that made it onto this blockchain
but if we can keep the pieces high
quality each pieces even if the website
just has the pieces and it's got no
technology behind it it'll start earning
capital and will start building
infrastructure too based on actual
demand that people have a proper were
going to break something and then we're
going to need support that technology
can help us with I'll pause there for a
second medic we can start going more
technical depending on where you're
interested I think I'm still kind of at
a loss on the overall concept so there
may be some stuff that you spoke about
but I mean you so you've mentioned it's
something instead of high school and
you've mentioned a building content is
the content that they're building I mean
is the learning experience the students
building the content or other students
expected to make use of the content the
students are generating the content and
for credit and so what I'm really doing
is if Bitcoin is a ledger of accounts
for for monetary value whatever you call
that value this is a this is a ledger of
accounts of these credits of academics
like if they're social capital academic
capital right so they'll upload a piece
of work and they get a credit I have a
question as well so yeah if a young
person was to decide to enroll in your
program right and and skip high school
and you know engage in a series and to
take a series of projects in exchange
for credits and they do really really
well they get all a bunch of credits
right so
those credits currently allow them to
access any higher educational
institutions are they recognized that's
all by any other higher education
institutions is there a process by which
that is underway for that to happen we
lost you again
I think he's frozen in 20 seconds so
probably or the final bit of my question
was am i completely missed any notion my
internet I think so yeah yeah I think
we're all seeing each other pretty well
so you guys yeah I promise you you will
get the notion when I'm gonna move in
the house and see if I make the
difference I will help answer and
Bentley's question is how the
cryptocurrency is generated so when they
do a project it's as I understand it
correct they create a credit so that's
how its generated but how is it right
and that is also how its dispersed so if
you're part of that project you get a
credit but if there's 20 people working
on a project to be at 120th of a credit
or do they it's generating 20 credits in
there then you don't not go to school
this is the key exams right do you guys
all know I don't know if you're all in
the u.s. you all know what I do know NEP
exams are but your connections we're not
in great volume like great sound quality
yeah it seems like you're I think is
worse okay so they are a teeny events
placement classes
yeah so I think his was more about I
guess that instead so then I don't know
I'm answering for him because he's he's
frozen because I did read the thing but
I didn't quite understand
it and also like you're generating
education content but are you watching
the education content is it being judged
on how you learn from it which means
we're introducing standardized tests
again right of like if you do one on
World War two and then people watch it I
was able to retain that information is
that what you're being judged on like is
it just there only one World War two one
or it would there be dozens and dozens
of World War two ones if someone else
wants to create one then so the part
that's confusing me about it is even
before that so you're it looks like
you're getting credits for creating
content not for viewing or using the
content in a day well then who what's
the point of making the content if no I
think the idea is people watch it cuz
it's fun like it's educational and
people and I can see that content
creation is probably one of the best
ways to learn something is by teaching
but but the thing is eventually all the
you know thousands of people need to
learn the same thing if their goal is to
create teaching content no one's going
to view that content which is fine but I
wouldn't call it creating content if no
one's gonna use it you know I'm saying
an exercise of constraints in general is
like what are you incentivizing dabber
we haven't are we doing that provider
right now but is it my back I don't know
I did see me here you know okay any
questions for you with so it's a
cryptocurrency that they that is created
when people generate content and it is
distributed based on the just that you
created content so if you create a video
that explains the history of World War
two and there was 10 people working on
that project and yes it gets a credit do
they each get one tenth of a credit or
do they not generates 10 because there
are 10 of them you guys are getting that
ok
the economic public we've skipped over
about your levels which is fine I love I
love that you guys are down there it's
so rare that I talk to people that are
interested there so it's a basic income
guarantee so they get a wallet that gets
a disbursement monthly for a small
number depending on what the inflation
schedule for the monetary value is right
there's it'll be easier or harder at
different times and I we can talk about
that monetary policy level too but it
would they would a few kids some kids
and each geographic region would get a
basic income guarantee for having
created whatever you can create metrics
incentivize right on they've
demonstrated they can master their
attention do quality work and that
people actually watched right so yeah I
think that's where jubblies at asking
the detailed lessons I'm still stuck at
the top level so regardless of how it
happens
the students create educational content
they are compensated for that if it
works well who's using that educational
content and is the compensation based I
mean yeah or is it metric like to get
that is it based on entertainment value
like YouTube what to watch the content
is it retention on whether it's kids
unique and there's not many people who
created content in that area like what
is the actual answer I don't know if
that's with Bentley's question if not
I'm sorry one final bit because the
question then becomes who becomes the
arbiter of whether or not it's deserving
of credit
thank you yes I can that's exactly right
right well I have a five page summary of
a lot of this I shared and we after the
second charity but let's try to get to
it now so let me start so let me just
try to remember bently the original and
I think we can weave into those and you
guys can guide me yeah maybe it'd be
good let this get like a two-sentence
description because I don't think I I
don't think the core I think everyone's
making assumptions on what the core is
yeah what really helps I think what
would and
answer it kind of intellectually what
helps us to see it to see it in action
to see it happening to see what was
happening at the school for the past
seven years and I have hundreds of
videos just to show you some of the
content so you get a sense of the kind
of quality content that can get produced
in this context and the content that I
have is mostly done at lunch after
school like not for credit because but
we did get it into the system itself and
this is part of the system this works
like the IP inside the current system
tops out some of some testing so you're
not not starting a new educational
system but I am taking the credit the
gold right now high school credits don't
mean shit sorry but they write depending
what school unless you went to that
great school which means you went to
that great elementary school which means
you went to that great principal in
preschool if you were at my school my
transcript doesn't mean anything to
college right they know I'm a second
chance school they're like those credits
are meaningless so I'm getting them
access to high-quality gold standard
credit that anybody the top level
schools could get or anybody can get
even if you dropped out of school you
can get one of these credits but it's
equivalent in AP tests you still have to
do high school equivalency the normal
way but it's a way to start
decentralizing who defines credits right
now the politics are favoring adult
interests not student interests so we're
and and at the core of it we're
replacing the standardized exam as the
unit of measurement and and we are
creating unit of measurement that is
very reductive right I'm really reducing
that one credit or zero credit and so
then we get to that question of who gets
to choose whether it's a credit or not
right so the whole system is based on
quality student works quality products
that is where the capital that is the
whole system so if we're going to
evaluate people to decide if they should
be the ones eligible to determine these
credits it's how many of these credits
and they built themselves how many
credits as a teacher working with
students how many of your students put
up credit they're losing audio again and
I back so frustrating
can you guys hear me again yeah feels
choppy but we can hear you
or maybe not Harlem why fine Harlem
Internet
but I think that goes to like a whole
other these technology credits are
accessible down the line having access
to the cameras having access to better
internet having access is going to make
the process much easier in their words
than it does in the ones that have less
less capacity or if you are at home to
do this yourself right I love like yeah
so that's my favorite question to answer
and I've got so that I work I work with
foster kids like this is my populations
if I don't serve my population and I
would be some sneaky bastard right the
way those basic incomes are organized
the contract the smart contract that
runs those basic income awards how you
determine who gets a basic income award
it's through these geographic zip codes
but digitally designed zip codes on that
the app that generates to decide what
area local area in and we use physical
location as a proxy for race so it's not
perfect but we then ensure that anybody
from each local area earns the same
number of credits right so that for one
neighborhood to earn a credit the other
local areas have to all earn a credit
also so if you want to earn more credits
in New York City you'd have to help the
geographic area that's having the most
trouble producing credits have them
produce credits and that helps
incentivize funds going to neighborhoods
that have more you know resource issues
so if I could get back to you said
quality the students producing quality
work when you say quality work are you
saying content educational content yeah
it's academic digital native after the
academic piece is where it has to be
focused
that's no my question is are they
creating training materials and they're
getting judged on that or are they
training are they what are they doing
what is the exam Majan NPR podcast you
know like well produced you know there
has research that has academic skills
has research they come up with their own
questions they're answering their own
questions
well we're focused I call their research
skills their use of attention their
mindfulness how do they deal with
revisions and frustration tolerance
right we're dealing with the skills not
Cerie to produce quality work and so
mindfulness has to be the first standard
right if we're talking about our human
attention so there's a lot packed into
it but it's they're creating no they're
creating content that is being judged
for the quality of their fact-checking
for sure right and for their research
and for the work that they did there's
three levels when I teach my teachers
how to teach we talked about three
levels the basic level you have
flashcard you have tests you have to do
that content level right and then
there's an application level where you
start thinking about what you just
digested and asking your own questions
and you know discussing it and finding
your position and then you create
something look I'm these credits only
capture that third extension level not
what the high schools do they capture
that next level that we did it laundry
after school mostly okay ap level I
don't know what you mean by okay so let
me let me see if I'm understanding they
produce content not edge not necessarily
educational content so they're there
they have a question they research and
then they produce some sort of content
that then other people could read or
benefit from right it could be video
written or whatever and then is this
process funded off of that content
creation or is that separate great is
the process funded let me make sure I'm
answering the right question what do you
mean explain what well where does money
come into it yeah yeah
you talk about giving these credits and
I guess the credits aren't actual money
but right right so I think that when
we're doing an analogue right now with
these event cycles that I'm planning out
we're simulating and so I'm using cash
that we have already we've already
raised but if we start building block
chains decentralized we start building
way from my my wife sister to start this
in Osaka we'd be giving people funding
Internet money right that means nothing
and they would be getting this basic
income every month and building these
useless coins but if it starts if
they're started to be network effects
enough people had these coins in their
hands they might all start advocating to
trade these coins and if we set them up
as a side chain of Bitcoin so there's a
clear conversion that people don't have
to figure that piece out it's already
figured
there's a chance one day they get traded
for something and then we're interfacing
from academic capital which is my focus
to so people would be putting in their
sweat equity and the teachers the
students all - you know - one day maybe
have these coins need something that the
master teachers the gatekeepers are an
important role that we haven't talked
about but its gatekeepers are people
that have reliably for a number of years
helped kids produce content that was of
quality to the right so it's recursive
and so then they become the gatekeepers
and they get money for there's a way for
them to get income from that they got be
funny money coins - right and so yeah so
it sounds like the main project is
giving students ap credit for practicing
and learning journalism right that's
that's a way to say it from the game
from the you know industrial context
that's a good perspective oh yes well I
don't see that that is industrial at all
I mean that could be just as much game
be yeah it's journalism is just
investigation and and putting things out
that's for the social studies credits
but like a scientist credit right we we
have talked about more it's gonna have
to be more like software engineering
code writing code I think there's a good
way to access to say muscle in your
brain that's mathy and so it could be
tutorial videos that nobody ever watches
unless the fuse kids really do a great
job explaining so we you know they you
have to deal with math separately so the
NPR example is just one type well money
kind of money does a lot of things that
I think requires some understanding just
understand the content you have to spend
some economic you know it was required
output always some sort of media so the
tells me that can be uploaded right but
it could be PDF all right it could be a
pazzo media or digital file it's a
digital file right yeah all right so it
never involves I don't know okay so I'm
so it doesn't fall into what we call
journalism but I would still I'd
generally call it that's a good way to
say it yeah I'd like that we had okay if
we have kids who have been known to lead
all the social movements are successful
arty
18 to 21 now 18 to 25 who I work with
and if they get academics they get
credit for this on an academic network I
think that yeah I think it's exciting if
they fill the gap that's right now in
our media landscape of deep
investigative stuff and their teachers
are fact-checking so now we have actual
you know meaningful fact-checking I
think that's exciting
yeah I think a generation I mean our
generation is kind of screwed like the
generation coming up being able to do
actual wow I can't even think of the
words to look critically at what's
happening to be able to connect each
other's and how that critical thinking
is huge that's it and even if we mess
this up and do a crap job of it that
measuring quality student work is still
doing better than a standardized test
and yeah when you said call it okay when
you said quality student work it's
really judging that final media that
they produce who is judging so these
gatekeepers and they would be getting
right that they would be getting this
funny money to that if it had value
would be you know and they are people
who have I think it should be ten years
look we have to start doing this and see
what it feels like but I think it should
be people that have a rate of acceptance
of their students when they upload a
piece the percentage of those pieces are
getting accepted onto the network that
you have a high percentage you know
success so you've kind of normalized
your practice with the existing
gatekeepers for a number of years so
you've invested many years of your work
but my teachers did this in their
classrooms as part as their practice you
know the ones that adopted it just did
it as part of it so they didn't do it
separately from school it was and it
helped their classrooms be more
interesting to social my social studies
teachers making movies is much more fun
than the crap they used to do going on
the street interviewing people like Vox
Pop was much more fun of a lesson than
listening to the teacher lecture so
write this stuff once we make it
available I can't imagine what the
community's going to do with it and it's
gonna the important thing is to build it
in a way that itself improves so my
stupid ideas disappear very quickly and
you know we forget that they ever
existed it's something much better can
show up and that's why we have to like a
you know open source version of that the
our demand of doing this in reality
builds the technology rather than trying
to build a tool first
and so built into the system even if the
cryptocurrency breaks it because it's
incentivizing the wrong thing built into
the system is a way to correct that
because then people can do investigative
journalism on that and can figure out a
way to maybe not have the cryptic wait I
couldn't hear any of what you just said
my know if it's constant oh wait no that
was Bentley who dropped out that having
the incentivization of any currency is
always going to be game of fat like it
can be problematic and so it's like
introducing an incentive and then seeing
what happens but in this case because
people can see what happens they can do
investigative journalism on it itself
and improve the system I hope so yeah
yeah I love that cool so I just want to
get back to your actual aspirations I
don't know how well we can do any of
these but that you want to revive the
nonprofit so I don't know exactly what
that entails
but yeah you didn't board of directors
and to do to do that I mean we can't do
that but we can maybe help you bring a
stronger find them and how to do that or
you also said self glitching your book
and then the site the website for events
which to me you said it was the number
one you won and I think that actually is
what we could we could help with as far
as not necessarily creating the website
but I know that um like this is the
thing that you're doing right like
digital uploads are the thing you're
giving currency to so having somebody
work on the website from within this
community right having them brainstorm
possibly what that looks like is it one
person coding it and then putting it up
and they get you know the currency or
having a group of them brainstorm like
to follow this process the lab right
imagine what a website looks like
then the studio of actually creating the
website and then the salon of like
launching the website so do you guys
know Zack Stein it's a lab with me he's
the one that I'm doing the lab part with
him and Nathan Snyder and I love Jubilee
I love you you that's exactly what we're
doing right we're using this model for
ourselves and so
one of us stands in the student role one
of them stands in the feature we call
catalyst role want to stand in the
gatekeeper we'd actually been using this
model to generate the content yeah so I
yeah I you you get it exactly you're
you're way ahead of me so the site and
it couldn't be something as simple as
helping me get on podcast once the book
is out but the site part tell me more
about how what you need to know for me
for the site I have an idea I have a
pretty good idea of but some some of it
understand funnels is the piece that I'm
not expert in I can just guide me
through maybe a phone call that to help
us walk through that would be helpful
yeah and then grunts I need you know if
you you know guys know that book
dividing pie or whatever it's called um
like I need we just need grunts at some
point to start doing the work but we'll
have that out of our events I'm not even
worried about that we'll have our first
event we already have that fund raised
like we will if nothing happens we're
going to move on and get a much bigger
community to ask these things of um
setting up that funnel I think is what's
most urgent for me because I want to be
able to send people to a property
internet property that they can then
give me their email address mm-hmm and
this is also um like what your focus
here on is upload about content but
there are so many supporting roles that
aren't upload about content like hey who
is the idea people who can think of what
what this website could look like right
cuz because if you have your idea and
then you have to hire someone whether
they're paid or not it they have to take
your vision and make it real whereas if
you have 10 a dozen kids getting
together and brainstorming what they
want this to look like and then they're
empowered to want to create it together
right and it's it's own thing which is
very different but you want to have
something before you even have that so
that you have a landing page which is I
think is although I'm not the person
talk about this I think Adriel intently
would be is like a landing page with
MailChimp account it's so so good
is there anything okay what can i is
there a question for me that I can
answer that can so I'm curious that
having earned these credits on what can
they be spent what can they get for you
what good are they so George Mason
University had a blockchain conference
there and I met the administration and
they're willing to accept them like AP
credits and we can work with the mastery
org folks they have a much bigger
community of schools that accept their
transcript which is exactly this work
their way they're a little bit ahead of
us so once this stuff comes out they're
just going to be ahead of everybody this
already exists elsewhere you're
replicating an existing model basically
yeah yeah model what are the limitations
of that that it can't roll out or it
could you're just filling a hole where
it hasn't got to yet kind of thing
there's a whole story in there I was
running a school we were doing this and
I had no interest in going beyond my
school and then I got taken out of the
school and all of my staff kind of fired
like we all got blown up so now we're
recreating that because we want to
continue that work that work was our you
know I moved in next door to the school
for a reason and all of my staff like we
we had something working together with
these specific people like I have a team
and we love working together so we're
just going to keep doing what we do
yeah but that's what happened is that
the department education and their
wisdom terminated our program I just had
a thought from before about using the
credits because the point is if they're
trainable then the currency becomes much
more valid right like credits are not
tradable the credits are like a high
school transcripts right it's you it's
your credentials and your skill set and
what it's all skills based so it's what
skills you've mastered or had
experiences with the currency that you
earn the basic income with yeah that's
the currency that you can do whatever
you want with if that's if you find ways
to trade it right that's two different
things the credits on the trend on the
blockchain the the credit ledger of
academic capital of your credits ones
and zeroes is just your transcript right
so you don't spend it you keep it
because you know something about like
getting hired and it could be a bonus or
the university could
give you a scholarship and it started
but that's based on the currency part
right so if you have this funny money
and nobody trades on an exchange a smart
employer if you watch these videos and
say wow these are in high quality I
would hire these people could say hey
I'll trade that funny money and give you
sign-on bonus with it and then they're
stuck with this funny money and then
there's more people fighting to make it
real right because then the university
or businesses that hold it would say hey
we need to get rid of this and maybe we
can get some money out of it so we just
wanted to spread as much as possible in
the community and that's exactly right
now digital cash is being designed we
haven't created that yet it's an
interesting times culturally to
introduce education at the foundation of
our digital cash economy right yeah okay
so I'm confused what if any link is
there then between these academic
credits and the currency earning the
academic credits gives you a and it's
the the the contract or the the logic
for doing it has to be totally
transparent everybody knows how it works
but there's some logic that certain
people are in the basic income by
earning these credits so most people
wouldn't be earning the money most
people would just be the credit the
smallest people if they were really
smart then they would they would
essentially a cash reward well being
yeah like high-level contributors or
whatever right with geography with it
with an equalising across geographies so
that one neighborhood can't be earning
them without the other neighborhoods
also earning them so it's like the top
earners in that neighborhood of
high-level contributors which there's
likely to be right what if there's an
uneven distribute use distribution of
high-level contributors across
neighborhoods
why are you flattening this thing I
don't understand um for to even mix
candy talked about you can be racist or
anti racist you can't be agnostic here
either intentionally trying to stop the
system from and I think but know there's
a point to this I think it is digital
economy to create a digital credit
system for digital education that
doesn't include diversity it's just like
our gene pool we want to mix our gene
pool to be healthy we need diversity to
educate our kids at least where I live
if I may say so is doing the exact
opposite of acknowledging diversity yeah
it's stamping out the diversity that the
diversity exists yeah there are more
people contributing here than there are
here therefore there should be more
people are only money here than there is
here right before actually reversing
that diversity in favor of some
preconceived notion of you know what I
mean we can't be racist or whatever if
you're if you're get to go to a top high
school where your parents are paying
tens of thousands of dollars the chances
are you can create better content
because quite frankly your parents can
pay someone to create better content for
you to do the editing and add the music
do those things for it and so yeah if
you're topping that the top 1% and maybe
there's 5,000 people that there's the
top 1% but if you're doing this on
library unlike the local library
computers and your your system doesn't
have I think this is a way to wait for
it and there is that built-in system of
the journalism reporting so that if it
is highly problematic rich people move
to the poor neighborhood so they can be
the talker and you can do all that
things then it's in the system to figure
that out and it's artificially posed I
mean it is artificial and you could I
agree with you that we're imposing and
think about it and we have to unpack
this a little bit but think about gender
we're just going to say that both
genders have to equally is that should
that be right should more guys do it you
more grosser and maybe you know I don't
know but we're saying let's just make
sure that we don't only do it to one
side
you know the Deaf could could I get I
think you talked about when I've looked
off can you quickly summarize your asks
in yes so um we just kind of where we
are in reality we're about to start
these sequence cycles of event here in
Harlem hoping to generalize them to
other people to be build to do the same
thing we have a non-profit that needs
some needs aboard to take it and say
will care for you it has money in the
bank re that we are going to spend for
this first cycle of events so it's that
landing page that's credible enough for
the nonprofit that we can ask board
members to come take it on and we only
need three really so I think we can do
it but I'm just the landing page to have
some credibility and somewhere that when
I talk about my book the book should be
coming out soon and I'll go on podcast
that I can send people to a page and get
their email addresses there
and you know our newsletter or our event
so you kind of so let me make sure I
understand yours you're saying you would
like to have someone help you create a
landing page with an email collection
form yes okay yeah I love how you write
a clip and I am I mean the other things
that I think you could use I think you
could use some work shopping on your
pitch or your description yeah or the
project which of course you'd have to
kind of handle when building a landing
page for this yeah yeah we have it down
to five pages and now we need to get it
down to a page with no words that are
the five pages the digital native
economic yeah that's problematic yeah
you need to get the idea across in two
sentences though somehow or other you've
got to get the flavor the essence the
spirit whatever of the idea across in
the first two sentences and then expand
from there right and I don't feel you I
don't feel you've got that yet I don't
feel you've got a clear distillation of
the the essence of the notion but I do
feel you have the resource to get you
there like and so maybe I'm wrong on
this but you have past students who have
been through a similar system that you
said those are the ones you're inviting
to the current event right so you have a
way to contact them you have their email
their phone number or something you have
a connection with them yeah I would say
reach out to them and ask how many of
you want to come in for a Saturday and
workshops they're going to know how to
make a landing page better than you know
they'd be like okay you know how to do
that
and they can create they can craft the
two sentences right they were part of
this to be able to say what they got out
of it which is the bigger piece anyway
right it's like what this students
experience going through it what they I
mean I think you know the documentary
World Peace and other fourth-grade
achievements and although I still don't
know how to play that game and I would
love to watching the kids go through and
then interviewing people thirty years
after who went through that process it's
like I want to play that game right
like that and generate what is elephant
I mean it's theirs right so why not have
them generate this and and make them
make the landing page and the invites
that'll make the landing page so buy
this in the dog but they'll do a way
better job than you can ever fucking do
surely I'm takin yeah yeah absolutely so
it's the board I guess I'm getting that
that stuff up and running and let me
think what yeah I mean I think we're
kind of rollin yeah I think just having
people that are passionate about this
especially you have people in New York
and you know what having engineers in
the room when we meet to then debrief
and see what they're seeing I would be
interested in if they're people in New
York yeah that well and I'm sorry to not
know you guys well enough I have a
different picture in education than in
specific areas but I would definitely
love help on the pitch and I'm getting
it down to that two sentences right
that's going to be the cover the front
page I think it is something along the
lines of the investigative journalism
meets at like what it gives the kids and
what a gives society I'll rolled into
two sentences that's not a lot right
education system that produces
investigative journalism as like our
regular citizenship right like something
along those lines that's where the old
students will like very much excel
because they've been talking about it
for the last however many years to a
whole bunch of people one or two of them
will have the messaging dials absolutely
absolutely they'll do a brilliant job
that's a brilliant idea that you come up
with fully there I mean it's no work for
you right what you got to do is get the
group of kids together and they'll do
all the work for you yeah messaging
that's for the website that's like
Instagram accounts and tik-tok and like
just like hey bring the people old and
the kids that I worked with 20 years ago
now are doing this professionally you
know and I couldn't book their time but
that alone even having some of the
projects or maybe like weird after
projects being things like tick-tock
then that builds your online presence
and that's a channel you're like wait
who made this and then you go do some
research you're like I can't believe
that's a project that's so cool right
right right yeah yeah and preaching to
the choir
[Laughter]
I wanted I've always wanted like an
access to kids that I can like teenagers
be like create this do this technology
but the more you can let go of your
vision of what cryptocurrency and how
that's going to work and the more you
can let them generate it the more
they're going to be behind it to do all
of it to be like hey this is this is how
it does there's like the foundation like
skeleton the blueprint and then they add
the meat or build the thing depending on
which of those notes you see what if
they like smoke cigars and drink whisky
whatever you know they'll do all the
work yeah and they have to because I
that's how that's why I'm a you know
principle and not you know cuz I don't
do any real work right it's it's how I
ran a robotics program that's why we
became top because I didn't do anything
I watched Netflix so your other issue
which I think we could all solve with
this group of people because they're not
all teenagers right there
overt I don't so wait a 25 is my who I
work with in the Devourer of Education I
work with 18 to 25 year old which is
perfect so the board of directors you
need three because it's a not-for-profit
are you one of those order directors no
I don't want to be okay so you want
three people to be on the board of
directors what is what do they need to
be to be on the board of directors what
age do they need to be what stage do
they need to live in do they need
I mean traditionally for a non-profit
they need to have money and they need to
have friend to have money okay the kids
don't have money it might not have
friends with money but they very likely
have they might have media presence and
they might be able to figure out the
marketing piece without needing the
money and the outside force right like
Bernie Sanders is making more money than
the other politicians because he's
tapping into this different way of
making money that is a tiny bit from a
bunch of people rather than a bunch from
from very few people right and I feel
like you frozen you can always we watch
this
that I'm having like the board of
directors if there is legal admits a lot
of what you said yeah no go ahead if
they have to be a certain age and the
onus of three is the minimum right you
don't necessarily and you don't need to
necessarily pay them because it's a
not-for-profit and so having them it's
like if you're generating what we just
talked about and having them come
together and create the website you can
also ask them of the board of directors
right maybe this is different Saturday's
or different outcomes of like hey who
wants to be on this board you have to be
18 if that's the rule you have to live
in the state of New York I don't know
what those rules are right yeah and then
by the way like full transparency we
need money like you know what I mean
like normally we would sit on this board
would be flan through mist so you have
millions of dollars and Friends of
billions of dollars but what can we do
that's different than that we still need
the money but how can we get the people
to sit here because when you're doing an
education one like to me you would want
the gatekeeper a student and a catalyst
you called them right like that would be
kind of perfect for it if there's only
three because you want each of the
stakeholders to be there representing
that and you want them to have the
perfect combination of traits so three
is probably not the number it's probably
going to end up being more than just
made you just yeah thank you I just got
I just had a breakthrough in that
there's I have a board that was on the
board for this nonprofit before I got
shut down when they shut down my program
the board shut down but I have a bunch
of people with money but I don't think
they're interested in Robert's Rules of
Order type board at this point but if
there was a board run by students and
they could observe and they could be the
money I think there would be much more
inclined to participate right so let the
students be in charge and let these guys
just watch the video afterwards or
whatever they don't have a big
commitment but they can just kind of
oversee and if they get inspired to give
they can ask their for you know like
they can do some of that but the kids I
think that's great yeah because we have
them I know I know that I've worked with
them for years and they want to work
with this so I we already have them um I
was trying to go in a different
direction with a different community but
maybe we mix them together yeah I feel
like the students that are magical in in
my head are also going to be great at
crowdfunding and like social media and
the things that are the new way to make
money which is like having 10
and fans give you a dollar giving ten
thousand fans give you 100 bucks each is
like you know mega mega money but that
they can tap into that and these people
are older and have connections and
resources as well they come through this
and they have a story with it which is
huge and we have frozen again so okay we
figured out your board we figured out
the side and website the third one was
the self-publishing - the book um which
I feel like I don't want to reach happen
to the kids but yeah like I mean they
could treat it I'll be like why are you
publishing a book oh so previous
previous records but it is something
that is tangible and will reach a
different generation and I mean I think
I'm hoping this generation still reads
the Pope it worth you generations away
from no longer reading at all but having
um how to self publish and I feel like
there are people in the game B space who
have self-published and can be a mentor
in that in that realm it's just about
posting it or and that's also with
together text mission write or meta
project like that's kind of the skills
of what is you know in this skill share
where you're not actually gonna do the
self-publishing for someone but to be
able to have a mastermind group or a
here's maybe we could set up something
that is here's how who's the expert in
self-publishing right and whose wants to
self publish a book come and have a
conversation about what you've learned
what you used what and maybe nothing
comes of it and maybe something I'm
guess come of it so I know you were
cutting out there
good job I just know I say we fixed your
nonprofit right you got the internet
sorry and we figured out the website and
I just figured out self-publishing for
you thank you I love the internet hold
on a second no but yeah you're right the
kids are they're not kids anymore but
yeah I think it's gonna go we just have
to keep going the way we're going mm-hmm
right to get the key yeah yeah so I
don't have anything else to say I'm the
book will come out soon I'm excited to
see get more feedback on that so that'll
be
and so when I was saying about
self-publishing was that I think there
are people in the game B space who have
self-published books and getting like to
find them as like a mentor to just kind
of what like hat most people in gave me
space are open for an hour-long
conversation about pretty much anything
searching was their area of expertise
self-publishing maybe isn't their area
of expertise but if they went through
that process there ahead of you right
which is kind of part of the soup that
would be stuff that's all I need right
because it's just with foster care in
all my life the more I can flatten the
learning curve by somebody else's
frustrating learning yeah right I just
I'm gonna star in a trip anyway but I'd
rather minimize yeah so with our kind of
more meta project we have this vision of
being able to scale share and being able
to reach out to the mentorship we don't
yet have of course that system this is
part of creating that system but I think
what we could possibly do is have an
hour-long conversation not with us cuz I
don't like we can one of us can
facilitate it because I ride are
interested me self-publishing I don't
have a thing I'm trying to self publish
but to put out there even if it's all
non experts that show up right even if
it's 501 it self publish a book and no
one's self-published a book you're still
gonna have more brain power in that room
yeah digital room then without that
right and so what have you tried and
where are you in this process but
hopefully there's also people who show
up who wanted to help with that process
right who are like look up a little bit
of an expert in that area that sounds
fun right yeah that's perfect
and so that's something that like we
could you could just put up in zoom or I
could put it up and zoom and then have
like a time period it works for you
clearly since you're gonna be there and
then finding other people might be
create so I'm going to be that nobody
shows up those things happen but it's
worth a try great yeah and I'm on
vacation all week for my schedule I can
accommodate anybody schedule so that's
yeah perfect yeah so just on the site on
the Facebook page on the game be
Facebook yeah I feel like there's enough
people I don't know anyone who's doing
like this podcast there's no one's kind
of said I'm trying to self publish but
but there
is I like there are so many writers it's
like Brent trying to self-publish
something I don't know let's just feel
like it is more article type stuff but
there's still another I think it'll be
great I would love to use the book I
don't need to make money from the book I
get paid enough I would love to use the
book to build the community so maybe PDF
versions to get the email address like
that kind of funnel is what I don't know
how to do well is it chapter if I can
weigh in PDFs are there different like
how do I make people feel like they're
getting something special and end up
mistakenly at one of our events if I can
get them to show to an event I'm good
from there right because every time a
kid to anybody walked into my school
like they'd never left we had that's how
we got so many volunteers and I think
just see because it's the kids it's not
me it's the kids they're irresistible
here in Central Harlem they really are
there they've experienced things that
none of us could imagine and they're
adorable at the same time mm-hmm Ike
you've already written this book right
so yeah doing something else isn't the
option you want to publish it because
it's something you've already done it's
just about getting it yeah and I I hold
no value in books I think I did it to
work on my own thought process I don't
expect anybody to read it but it does go
into the details of everything we've
been talking about here and historical
context does the other option decides a
one-off conversation which is how this
probably will start is put into
something out and seen do want to come
to is like in that conversation having
an ongoing having a conversation of who
wants an ongoing like um co-op or
co-op Council on self-publishing right
like how if you're meeting weekly or
bi-weekly up like hey what have we done
that's next because as you're all
working through that process together to
self publish your book you're gonna come
up with obstacles and help each other
yeah great all right great yeah and
those things might even already exist
outside of the game be space like in
facebook groups of like people
self-publishing their books right that
are there and in fact tapping into that
and then inviting those people but then
they're not necessarily game be
practicing rule Omega or they might be
because they might be like these
something that comes naturally to them
yeah that's great yeah if and if it can
be like an hour week that I get together
with people to talk about and we use
that to drive the drive through
forward that's perfect very doable yeah
thank you guys so I would love to hear
in two seconds like what brings you guys
to give of your time to somebody like me
right like what makes you sit up in bed
on a Saturday morning and do this what
you guys are out to create something I
would love to understand it a little bit
well in case you couldn't tell I just
have the time of my life I love creating
solutions for other people here you go
here you go and I think that a lot of
what I do like problem solving and
having discussions and having
conversations and I will let everybody
else answer for themselves yeah I
I'd like Julia enjoy hearing new ideas
and giving off-the-cuff armchair
feedback - not that you've only said it
that way that's the way I do it and then
so I like helping out and then also I
have several of my own projects and so
this is kind of a karmic way of building
a community of people that support each
other is by you know giving first so yes
that's that's that's kind of my
motivation yeah for me fairly similar to
Bentley we're about a project that
brought me into the game be space but
over time I think we all sort of
independently noticed oh there's a lot
of projects here and everyone's
struggling in a lot of the same ways and
when you hear us talk about the meta
project it's a project to help structure
and sort of organize all those projects
what you know so we can stop remitting
the wheel if there's ten of us let's all
get together figure it out one so that
we can all reuse that information to me
that's the purpose of these meetings is
so that like if you know I have the same
challenge and you have have the same
challenge with brainstorm start to see
you know the common themes over time and
then start to build a playbook for
here's what any project can do and
here's what certain projects might want
to try as well yeah
and for me I've got a particular
interest because it was a
transformational project in education
and as a teacher who bemoans constantly
what education has actually become you
know I was interested on that level and
also everything that Jubilee said about
forming new connections I mean that for
me the notion of cross-pollination
between these groups is really important
you know what I mean like the result of
this conversation this group I'm part of
a few other groups as well maybe
something that's come up here today will
be you know something that really helps
to move another conversation along you
know what I mean something I've learned
here and so on and so on you know what I
mean and these things all linked
together in entirely unpredictable ways
and so the more we can do this the
better as far as I'm concerned it's an
end no no that's not sure it's not an
end in itself but it might as well be
because it creates soil for all sorts of
possibilities in the future that we
can't possibly know of you know and so
it is almost an end in itself and to
think for me to interact with you guys
you guys are kind of like a lab right
for me the people the gatekeepers that
would be right the people causing other
people right and it to think that a
group of people like you with your
generous hearts are would be the ones
working out that how to define quality
work working out the nitty-gritty of how
to decide what work is quality what work
isn't versus Cuomo and the politicians
who spend no time and lawyers who've
never walked into an effing school
building and then to work the teachers
that I work with they always say like if
this is what teaching is like I would I
would you know like love being a teacher
but it's not and some of them have out
have retired early because the
industrial system is such malpractice I
grew up in the Waldorf schools is
Rudolph Steiner schools and I was lucky
enough to grow up in a system that
opened my heart and and made me
passionate about doing work you know and
but that and I want to share that right
so it's always you know absolutely be
the greatest job in the world teaching
absolutely a privilege and an honor and
a non-stop pleasure it really should
they've done anything they can't stop it
being there motherfuckers preparing it
should pay more yeah yeah yeah yeah
that's super honestly honestly if you
could actually
fully experienced the joy of teaching as
it should be you know I mean I think a
lot of teachers will do it for half the
money you know dollars enough to cover
my building that that's that's that's
all it's enough you know yeah I mean
yeah the best teachers I had all had a
spouse that could support them sorry
that's teachers I had all had a spouse
that could support them
right hi hi so there was no one it's not
that they need it is not in where I live
it does not pay a living wage it's not
just about tracking people it's that the
teachers are so distracted by having to
figure out how to keep their lives
running that they cannot focus on the
students and then I thought about energy
wise they're in a coercive system that
is out to demoralize and punish them but
yeah yeah so they're all doing it for
altruistic needs and I mean for being
altruistic every single one of them I
believe and then they they run out more
energy right and then they have to do
something else anyways it's like we're
taking resources so everyone's resources
are met everyone's basic needs are met
and the people in teaching and we're
gonna be the people who want to teach
and then everyone has a spouse it's us
it's everyone helping everyone be that
yeah it's like me a better teacher yeah
don't don't to here my list of seven
things now bendy this would be a good
spot to put them in especially well in
the dance here as well yeah this is this
other laptop so this is this is and this
is just so this is just a selection
right I mean give me an hour or two and
I could write 20 pages on this anyway so
one standardizes and this is sorry this
is the damage caused by standardized
testing right this is well this is about
pre-k the fire my friend oh no no I
realize that standardizes narrows
curricula inevitably making them content
rather than process driven discourages
originality critical thinking and
challenge promotes a fear of failure and
a reluctance to experiment D emphasizes
the arts as they cannot be easily
measured demotivates both teachers and
students sets up the majority of
students and indeed schools to fail
rewards conformity in obedience and
punishes difference those are those are
seven that I came up with in like 30
you know means right and all those same
characteristics are great in a factory
context to make our cars I want all
those things to be there to that I have
a safe car to drive in but not to build
a human being you know yeah I mean this
isn't from the 1840s I think something
like that isn't that I mean it's that
yeah yeah I think yeah I think we're out
of time I think there's a lot to tease
about that so that'd be an interesting
to tease out from that conversation to
have a discussion some other time having
an event comes be inspired yeah I
guarantee a I guarantee you will be
alright
I'd love to memory New York yeah
I'd never allow for that to be part of
my life and yes I will come to one of
those events or you guys make so much
money you want to bring us over so
because and also an actual I will be in
New York and March so we'll have to yeah
get oh yeah absolutely
I'm in Harlem my whole life in Harlem so
if you're anywhere but I can go anywhere
- yeah all right let's take a body you
know then weekend thanks for joining us
fun on Saturday morning or you been for
Eric and